# PhD Candidate. MSc. Albi Dode



### Software Engineer & DPO

Keplerstraße 30/3, 89073 Ulm, Germany | +491638587648 | info@albidode.info

in linkedin.com/in/albidode 😵 albidode.info

### **Summary**

Software Engineer/Developer, IT support, Manual Tester, Technical Writer, and Data Protection Officer providing technical support, developing software programs, web sites, giving information security/DPO consulence. I have knowledge in Agile methodology for leading teams in achieving excellence in client satisfaction, productivity, and profitability. Firm mindset with a drive to find solutions to new problems. Strong analytical skills and detailed to project's requirements. Adaption well in groups and a willingness to understand the various roles played by fellow team members. Perform tests and find ways to eliminate bugs in the programs. Build interactive and dynamic websites. Experience with remote projects during master studies. Bachelor in Computer science (State University of New York) and Master in Software Engineering (Mälardalens högskola Västerås).

PhD in progress: "The Development of a generic framework for mobile data sensing and mobile patient intervention" (Universität Ulm).

### Work experience

PhD 2019

ESIT & University of Ulm

Development of a generic framework for mobile data sensing and mobile patient intervention for tinnitus patients.

PHP Developer - BlueScreen

2019 - 2019

\* Responsible for writing server-side web application logic \* Develop back-end components, connect the application with other web services, and support the front-end developers by integrating their work with the application. CI/CD processes .

Technical Writer - Ericsson

2018 - 2019

\* Supporting documents to communicate complex and technical information \* Explain complex information in a clear and concise manner and working with the staff to ensure accuracy of product functionalities. \* ArborText TagTool.

Contribute to the establishment and evolution of the digital organization.

Work together with the product owner and other team in an agile environment. Investigate and suggest new technologies and solution.

Document several IT systems.

### **Skills**

Methodology

Agile, Scrum

Testing

Jira, JUnit

Databases

Firebase, Oracle, MS Access, SQL, MySQL

inebase, oracie, morrecess, sqc, mye

Languages

C++, C#, VB .Net, Java, HTML/SQL/PHP/Codelgniter,R

**Applications** 

Weka, SPSS, Windows & Linux Environment, Active Directory, Exchange / Outlook, MS Office, NetBeans, Eclipse, Visual Studio, ArborText, GitLab, Dita XML, ArborText TagTool, Codelgniter

### **Experience**

- Ability to multitask in a fast paced environment.
- Good interpersonal skills, problem solving and organizational skills.
- Good phone and email etiquettes.
- Willing to work in a flexible schedule.
- Excellent customer relation skills in order to provide flawless support for them.
- Proficient in Windows and Linux.
- Good working knowledge of all desktop applications and malware

IT and DPO - qPharmetra Sweden

2018 - 2018

- \* Cisco Meraki for cloud management for security, networking, and application control. \* Inform about security risk for Microsoft products.
- \* Gather requirements and identify the costs and the time needed to implement the IT project. \* Supporting, monitoring and maintaining workplace technology and responding to users' requests for help.

\*Support for Office365 and Web technologies.

Identify and understand business needs.

Contribute to the establishment and evolution of the digital organization.

Maintain and develop/refactor existing software. Perform code reviews. Support cloud and VPN services.

### Master thesis - Manual Tester

2017 - 2017

### Accedo TV

Part of master thesis- Reviewing and analyzing system specifications. Executing test scripts and reviewing results for finding the effective variables for predicting faults in the code. Mobile, PC platforms.

Execute effective test plans and evaluation of product testing phases.

Documentation and troubleshoot of errors with different systems iOS, Android.

### Lecturer - Albanian University Tirana

2015 - 2015

Lecturer and for one semester in Tirana and Berat for the subjects : Computer Architecture & Web Applications.

IT support - Albanian Psychologists Association

2014 - 2015

\* Made a website using in HTML/PHP/MySql and a documentation content management system using Java. \* SEO optimization.

Transform abstract problems into concrete roadmaps for new digital solutions.

Design and develop new software.

Build dashboards, create reports and analyze data. Communicate results to organization board.

Technical Support Specialist - Albanian Business Partner 2012 - 2014

\*Meet with the client to determine customization requirements. \*Work with client to define the scope of the project. \*Clarify clients system specifications, understand their specific work practices. \*Travel to customer's site. \*Diagnose and refine challenges & opportunities \*Help clients with change-management activities \*Purchase systems where appropriate \*Design, test, install and monitor new systems. \*Facilitated network support for hospitals in Tirana for a software written in Java. \* Supported different troubleshoots within Windows systems.

Introduce and implement relevant framework and tools.

Design, develop and evaluate new tech trends according to business needs.

### Freelancer

applications.

- Ability to load and troubleshoot various software and hardware systems.
- Good knowledge of various networking concepts.

### Languages

English: C1

Italian: B2

Spanish: B1

Swedish: A1

French: Basic words

German: A2

### Certification

GDPR - DPO

Different websites for private companies using HTML/PHP/MySql.

Helped several companies setting up: Office 365, Skype for Business, SharePoint, Active Directory

### **Education**

Bachelor in Computer Science

2010 - 2014

University of New York Tirana & State University of New York

Thesis: Hotel Booking Android application

Master of Science in Software Engineering

2015 - 2017

Mälardalen University

Under Erasmus Mundus Scholarship

Thesis: Effectiveness of fault prediction

Download PDF - DIVA Portal

Thesis conducted at Accedo Broadband AB Stockholm

### **Contributions**

Certification from *FER University* for high results in Distributed systems course - 2017.

Finalist at "From Gjirokastra to Gjirokastra" competition - 2014.

Rotary Club Tirana - Charity work for families in needs in Mirdita - 2013.

### **Core Competencies**

- Scrum/Agile
- Project Management
- Troubleshooting
- Analytical skills
- Group work
- Knowledge of intended audience

- Coding
- Technical Support
- Quality Assurance
- Research in new technologies
- Multitasking
- Adapt in teams with different cultures

### **Articles and publications**

Technology and democratic citizenship connection in Albania - UNIEL - 2014

AlbiDode, Elvira Dode

 $https://www.researchgate.net/profile/Albi\_Dode/publication/314235740\_Technology\_and\_democratic\_citizenship\_connection\_in\_Albania/links/58bc3f22a6fdcc2d14e58f21/Technology-and-democratic-citizenship-connection-in-Albania/links/58bc3f22a6fdcc2d14e58f21/Technology-and-democratic-citizenship-connection-in-Albania/links/58bc3f22a6fdcc2d14e58f21/Technology-and-democratic-citizenship-connection-in-Albania/links/58bc3f22a6fdcc2d14e58f21/Technology-and-democratic-citizenship-connection-in-Albania/links/58bc3f22a6fdcc2d14e58f21/Technology-and-democratic-citizenship-connection-in-Albania/links/58bc3f22a6fdcc2d14e58f21/Technology-and-democratic-citizenship-connection-in-Albania/links/58bc3f22a6fdcc2d14e58f21/Technology-and-democratic-citizenship-connection-in-Albania/links/58bc3f22a6fdcc2d14e58f21/Technology-and-democratic-citizenship-connection-in-Albania/links/58bc3f22a6fdcc2d14e58f21/Technology-and-democratic-citizenship-connection-in-Albania/links/58bc3f22a6fdcc2d14e58f21/Technology-and-democratic-citizenship-connection-in-Albania/links/58bc3f22a6fdcc2d14e58f21/Technology-and-democratic-citizenship-connection-in-Albania/links/58bc3f22a6fdcc2d14e58f21/Technology-and-democratic-citizenship-connection-in-Albania/links/58bc3f22a6fdcc2d14e58f21/Technology-and-democratic-citizenship-connection-in-Albania/links/58bc3f22a6fdcc2d14e58f21/Technology-and-democratic-citizenship-connection-in-Albania/links/58bc3f22a6fdcc2d14e58f21/Technology-and-democratic-citizenship-connection-in-Albania/links/58bc3f22a6fdcc2d14e58f21/Technology-and-democratic-citizenship-connection-in-Albania/links/58bc3f22a6fdcc2d14e58f21/Technology-and-democratic-citizenship-connection-in-Albania/links/58bc3f22a6fdcc2d14e58f21/Technology-and-democratic-citizenship-connection-in-Albania/links/58bc3f22a6fdcc2d14e58f21/Technology-and-democratic-citizenship-connection-in-Albania/links/58bc3f22a6fdcc2d14e58f21/Technology-and-democratic-citizenship-connection-in-Albania/links/58bc3f2a6fdccc2d14e68f2a6fdccc2d14e68f2a6fdccc2d14e68f2a6fdccc2d14e68f2a6fdccc2d14e68f2a6$ 

#### The Values of Civic Education through Information Technology- Albanian University – 2015

http://www.mcser.org/journal/index.php/ajis/article/view/7397

https://doi.org/10.5901/ajis.2015.v4n2s2p15

Albi Dode, Elvira Dode

#### Teenagers Problems Related with Social-Networking - Epoka University - 2015

Albi Dode, Genta Rexha, Lediona Nishani

Proceedings of the 5th International Conference on European Studies 5th ICES

http://dspace.epoka.edu.al/handle/1/1316

#### An Android-based Application for Mining Customer Satisfaction 2015

International Scientific Conference COMPUTER SCIENCE'2015

08-10 September 2015, Durrës, Albania

Albi Dode, Erind Bedalli

http://cs.tu-sofia.bg/conf/ComputerScience15\_Program.pdf

#### **NETWORK SECURITY THROUGH VULNERABILITY ANALYSIS 2016**

Albi Dode, Silvester Hasani

http://www.inderscience.com/jhome.php?jcode=ijkms

#### Effectiveness of fault prediction - Review - Albanian University - 2016

Albi Dode, Genta Rexha, Kinan Dindan

http://www.albanianuniversity.al/al/njoftime/401-konferenca-nderkombetare-dhjetor-2016

### Assessment of an IT network security with information gathering tools - Albanian University 2015

Albi Dode, Silvester Hasani

https://www.researchgate.net/publication/314235536\_Assessment\_of\_an\_IT\_network\_security\_with\_information\_gathering\_tools

#### **Page Rank Algorithm**

Albi Dode, Silvester Hasani

http://www.iosrjournals.org/iosr-jce/pages/19(1)Version-3.html

https://doi.org/10.9790/0661-1901030107

http://www.researcherid.com/ProfileView.action?

returnCode=ROUTER.Unauthorized&queryString=KG0UuZjN5Wlte3fin7unE58Fn9h7A31B3YOFDl0078c%253D&SrcApp=CR&Init=Yes

http://journals.indexcopernicus.com/issue.php?id=11660&id\_issue=886308

## Why do programmers prefer Opencl for Gpu programming? - European University 2016

Albi Dode, Genta Rexha

https://www.academia.edu/36823300/Why\_do\_programmers\_prefer\_Opencl\_for\_Gpu\_programming

### The challenges of implementing General Data Protection Law (GDPR) 2018

Albi Dode

https://www.researchgate.net/publication/327829348\_The\_challenges\_of\_implementing\_General\_Data\_Protection\_Law\_GDPR

### Smartphone Apps in the Context of Tinnitus: Systematic Review 2020

Muntazir Mehdi, Constanze Riha, Patrick Neff, Albi Dode, Rüdiger Pryss, Winfried Schlee, Manfred Reichert, Franz J Hauck

https://www.mdpi.com/1424-8220/20/6/1725/htm

# Smartphone and Mobile Health Apps for Tinnitus: Systematic Identification, Analysis, and Assessment 2020

Muntazir Mehdi, Michael Stach, Constanze Riha, Patrick Neff, Albi Dode, Rüdiger Pryss, Winfried Schlee, Manfred Reichert, Franz J Hauck

https://mhealth.jmir.org/2020/8/e21767/

### Contemporary and Systematic Review of Smartphone Apps for Tinnitus Management and Treatment

Muntazir Mehdi, Albi Dode, Rüdiger Pryss, Winfried Schlee , Manfred Reichert and Franz J. Hauck

https://www.preprints.org/manuscript/202009.0620/v1

### **Conferences**

British Tinnitus Association Conference - London September 2019

R Workshop - Sietges, Spain October 2019

